SRI HARSHA CHILAKAPATI

Bengaluru, India · +91 9494607964

sriharshachilakapati@gmail.com · goharsha.com · github.com/sriharshachilakapati

A self-enthusiast developer who is interested in developing applications for platforms of interest such as Android, Web, Desktop and also iOS. Had experience in building real-time applications optimized for performance. I'm always interested in exploring tech.

EXPERIENCE

10TH FEBRUARY 2022 - 5TH SEPTEMBER 2023

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER II

APNATIME TECH

- Developed architecture based on MVVM + Clean Architecture for the most important parts of the Apna app, Job Feed, Job Search and Job Details and launched Apna Jobs 2.0. Increased user adoption by 46%.
- Worked on the Pan India job liquidity story, which by allowing users to apply in other cities, increased the screened leads by 4%.
- Profiled app code and refactored to reduce overdraw from 11x to 3x and brought frametimes down to 14ms per frame.
- Found and prevented an attack vector which allowed malicious actors to peep on CleverTap campaigns by implementing custom obfuscator. Contributed fix back upstream to <u>CleverTap SDK</u>.
- Implemented custom RecyclerView ItemDecorations to do Figma Perfect Shadow Rendering and Group Background Rendering using Finite State Machines.

1ST OCTOBER 2019 – 10TH FEBRUARY 2022

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

JUSPAY

- Optimized Gradle build pipeline to make builds faster by 65% from 2 minutes to 13 seconds.
- Created new SDK architecture for Hyper SDK 2.0, a flagship product.
- Created a Chrome DevTools plugin to debug native Android Views.
- Wrote 2 Gradle plugins to generate code and assets for merchants resulting in reduction of merchant specific flavours in HyperSDK.

1ST JUNE 2018 – 30TH SEPTEMBER 2019

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER JUSPAY

- Worked on payment pages for Ola Money, Cred and Big Basket.
- Took ownership of Payment Pages for Foodpanda and Bounce (Android & iOS).
- Created the VIES merchant demo app (Android) at Juspay.

4TH DECEMBER 2017 – 31ST MAY 2018

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEERING INTERNJUSPAY

- Implemented 2 screens (Settings & User Profile) in BHIM UPI App.
- Worked on Android module of Presto UI called Mystique, which is a React Native like framework for Juspay.

PROJECTS

- <u>FakeCaller (A POC app to demonstrate working of TrueCaller)</u>
- SilenceEngine (Game Engine for Desktop, HTML5 and Android)
- WebGL4J (WebGL bindings for Java language using GWT)
- GWT-AL (An OpenAL implementation on top of Web Audio API)
- YT Private Subscriptions (iOS App that allows to subscribe to YT channels without logging in)
- <u>EasyJSON (Easy to use small (11 KB) JSON library</u> for Java)
- <u>EasyXML (Easy to use small (13 KB) XML library</u> for Java)

SKILLS

PROFICIENT IN

Java, Kotlin, JavaScript, Swift, PureScript, Android Development, iOS Development

FAMILIAR WITH

C, C++, C# and 24 other Programming Languages

CAN COMMUNICATE IN

Telugu, English, Hindi, Kannada, Tamil

EDUCATION

NOV 2021

SYSTEMS EXPERT, ALGOEXPERT.IO

MAY 2021

IOS DEVELOPER NANODEGREE, UDACITY

FEB 2021

ANDROID KOTLIN DEVELOPER NANODEGREE, UDACITY